Unknown: Hello everyone, this is
Luke Thompson and you're
listening to a phrasal verb day.
This is where I attempt to teach
you a phrasal verb every day for
a year. And yes, this project is
still ongoing. A phrasal verb a
day is back and in this episode,
I'm going to teach you some more
common phrasal verbs as we
continue on this mission to get
to 365 days of phrasal verbs.
Now I'm going to talk to you
about phrasal verbs with the
word pop. And there are a lot.
Also I want to say that a
phrasal verb a day will continue
after this episode, but not
here. In this RSS feed. All the
new episodes of phrasal verb day
will appear in the Luke's
English podcast app, and online
at teacher luke.co.uk/p V. Okay,
over the next days or weeks 10
more episodes of a phrasal verb
a day will appear in the app.
I'll talk to you more about that
in a moment. First, let me just
remind you of this project and
what this is all about. So this
is where I teach you phrasal
verbs, these essential bits of
natural English. Originally, I
plan to do one of these every
day. But after a couple of
months, it became impossible to
do that every day. I've added
more episodes over the years.
And we're currently on number
139. I think in fact, this one
that you're listening to
listening to right now is number
140. Well, it's time to revive
this series and do so in the
Luke's English podcast app,
which I expect is where you're
listening to this. If you're not
listening to it, then move over
to the app because that's where
the new episodes will arrive. So
what I do in these episodes is
explain and demonstrate various
phrasal verbs. I think the best
way to learn vocabulary is to
hear it being used in context
with vivid examples. And I
always try to do this sometimes
having a bit of fun with some of
the scenarios. And all of it's
designed to help you learn these
crucial bits of English. Phrasal
verbs are crucial because this
is exactly the way that native
speakers use the language. But
learners of English have trouble
with them because they are
idiomatic. They're tricky in
structure. And they don't exist
as grammatical forms in their
languages. But let's carry on
them with a big one. And we're
looking at the word pop. So
these are phrasal verbs with
pop. This is extremely common
and quite versatile. It's
absolutely one of the most
common little phrases used every
day all over the country. It's
informal, but it's polite. It's
kind of nice and light. So let's
hear about it. And you get we're
going to hear phrases like pop
in pop off, pop on pop out, pop
over, pop round and pop up as
well. So pop P O P, it can mean
lots of things. It can mean to
go it can mean to move
something, it can mean to leave,
to visit, to appear lots of
different things, let's go
through them all we'll start
with pop in, this is maybe the
most common one pop in also pop
into a place. And to pop in
means to go somewhere, just for
a quick visit, just go somewhere
quickly, you go somewhere you
stay there for only a short
time. So you pop in. For
example, you might say, I'll pop
in later. And, you know, I'll
pop in later and talk to you
about the podcast, for example.
I'll pop in this afternoon, you
know, I managed to pop into the
bank to get all that paperwork
done. For example, okay, uh,
popped into the blue laundry, or
popped into, you know, the
supermarket, you know, or do you
want to pop in later. And we'll
talk about that thing. For
example to pop in. Also, you
have pop in to do, for example.
So, you know, I popped in to
make a reservation at the
restaurant. Okay, that's pop in,
then we have pop on. And this
means to move something to put
an item or, or to put something
on a particular in a particular
place to pop it on the tape,
just pop that on the table, just
pop it on the shelf there,
that's great. Just pop that on
the back of the chair. Okay, pop
on to put also to put an item of
clothing on, you know, just just
pop your coat on. And we'll go
out again, it's so common, it's
just strikes me as being so
common that that kind of
language, so I just, you know,
thought we'd just pop out to the
shops. So just pop your shoes
and coat on and off we pop. Just
very common language and it
sounds quite nice. It's
informal, but that's not a bad
thing. It's informal, but it's
kind of the right kind of tone.
You might hear a doctor say the
word pop, it's exactly the sort
of thing a doctor would say, to
try and put you at ease. So just
put yourself down on the chair.
They've just want to just just
pop your clothes off and just
pop onto this. This bed here.
Just pop this into your mouth.
You know that To the sort of
thing that doctors say, anyway,
we've had pop in and pop on,
just pop your coat on, let's go
for a walk. Okay. We also have
pop out, which is very common,
meaning to leave quickly or just
to leave for a short time. You
know, so where's Dave? Oh, he's
just popped out, it will be back
in a minute. Dave's just popped
out, he'll be back in a minute.
Okay, I'm just popping out, you
know, just popping out to get
some windscreen washer fluid.
Anyone want to join me breath of
fresh air, you know, just
popping out to the to the
carriage, for example, popping
out to do something I'm just
popping out to post a letter,
I'll be back in a few minutes
pop out to do something. Okay,
that's to pop out pop over. That
would be to visit a someone at
their house for a short time.
I'll just I'll pop over later
on. And we'll have a cup of tea.
Okay, it's a bit like to pop in
or pop in later, I'll pop over
later over suggesting that you
know the distance between where
you are now and where the person
lives or pop over later on.
Okay, pop round is also the same
kind of thing, basically, to
visit someone quickly or for a
short time. It's like pop in,
pop over or pop round. Okay, so,
you know, pop rock, Could you
Could you do me a favor? Could
you pop round later, I just want
to ask you something. Okay, or
pop round to do something. I'm
just popping around to ask you
if you've got those papers that
we're talking about. Lots of
lots of distribution of papers
going on in this episode isn't
there, everyone's popping in and
out with different papers, then
we've got to pop up. And this
means to appear quickly or
suddenly to pop up. Okay, I
mean, you know this from
computers, because when you're
using a computer, sometimes you
get popups these are like
annoying adverts that pop up
they just appear quickly. And
you have to kind of try and
close them pop up adverts. But
pop up just means you know,
arrive or appear quickly. Like
this issue pops up sometimes. Or
that the you know, the question
of the papers popped up again at
the meeting. And flowers might
pop up as well. You know, in the
spring you start to see flowers
popping up here and there. Also,
we use pop up as an adjective
like a pop up book, or a pop up
card, which has pictures inside
that stand up when you open the
pages. A pop up toaster pushes
the piece of bread up so the
toast pops up when it's ready.
Okay, and a pop up ad as well as
we said. So there you go. Lots
and lots of different phrases
with pop there that I've just
been through. Now normally these
phrasal verb episodes are a bit
shorter than this. Normally,
they're just a few minutes. As I
said earlier, there will be
about 10 More of these phrasal
verbs. Episodes arriving soon,
but they won't arrive here in
the phrasal verb a day podcast
feed. So if you're listening to
this in the Apple podcast app,
or some other app, they these
phrasal verb episodes will no
longer appear there. Instead,
they'll pop up in the Luke's
English podcast app. So get the
app for your smartphone. You can
find it in the app store for
iOS, Apple devices and Android
phones. So you can find it in
the in the app store there just
download it and then in the app,
you can use the side menu to
find the phrasal verb category
and all the episodes will be
there. You can also access and
download the episodes online
from teacher luke.co.uk/p V. The
transcript collaboration for
these episodes is also still
going. So if you'd like to
contribute a transcript to a
phrasal verb episode, go to my
website, and then episodes and
then hover over phrasal verb
podcast and click transcript
collaboration and that's where
you can get involved. But for
now, I just like to say have a
very good day or morning or
evening or nights that this has
been an episode of a phrasal
verb day and I'll speak to you
again on the podcast soon but
for now. Goodbye bye bye bye