Peter: Hey, what's up, everybody, Peter McKinnon here. Welcome back to yet another video.
We're still in the office. This is a different part of the office studio, what have you.
I got to do a studio tour, I still got to do it. But I wanted to just get in front of you guys and say hello. It's been a little while.
I've been uploading less. I feel like I've been uploading a lot. I had two bangers last week. We haven't seen them go check them out.
But I wanted to chime in and say, how are you? I've missed you. Make sure my mic is facing my face a little bit more.
I just got back the other day from the Grand Prix in Montreal, which was amazing. I shot the whole thing on film,
I thought it'd be interesting shooting the world's fastest sport, the slowest way.
And those two things marry together might make for some interesting moments caught on film, which I certainly did.
It's it's pretty cool. So yes, I am still in love with the film process. Still learning still shooting a ton,
I gotta say, of the last 20 years shooting, I really feel like I've had the biggest leap of improvement and growth as a photographer since I started shooting film again.
So it's been very great. It's been very inspiring. And I've even seen some messages from you guys, and DMs and beating you at the race and at the shop here
that you've also been inspired to pick up a film camera and throw a few rolls through it yourself, which makes me super excited.
So if that has been something you're doing, I'm literally pumped for you. Because it's been so great for me and my creativity,
I have no shortage of ideas for it. It's just I don't want to just completely bombard you with film stuff because digital still exists. And it's still important and it still has a place.
So we'll be trying to balance the two. Over the coming months.
I was in Atlanta, but three weeks ago at a convention called blade, which is just basically where a ton of manufacturers and makers from around the world get together and sell knives.
It's It's pretty crazy. We made a video about it. It's over on the pirate channel. We've resurrected that and we'll be posting there again as well.
So there's a lot of things going on a lot of ingredients in the soup that we are making a little spoiler alert, we built a pirate ship. Very, very cool.
But the next thing I'm very excited about is I'm learning how to tattoo Yes,
I'm not gonna become a full blown tattoo artists that is a lifetime endeavor.
That is something you are constantly working on the skill and determination and requirement and sacrifice for something like that to get to the level
I still haven't beat my high score. And that reminds me literally every eight minutes that I have not
I'm nowhere near Andrew Wilson's level who is my neighbor, by the way who tattoos daily.
So I get to wander in and just see what he's up to. And sometimes he lets me tattoo him which is which is pretty great.
But it's super nerve wracking. My hand was shaking.
I the last time my hands shook that much is when I was doing card tricks for people for a paid event and it was the first time ever doing them live and you're so nervous.
I probably shouldn't have coffee before I do it. So next time I will do that but he just got me this new machine and it comes in this sick little box his friends over at FIT hooked all this stuff up.
So FIT. Thank you very much for for helping me start my tattoo journey but check this thing sanitizes the machine
I want to get good at a couple little things that I want to practice a pizza slice a coffee cup, just some fun little things that I think people would enjoy getting tattooed on them and maybe maybe
you'll come get tattooed by me we'll hang out talk cameras, bang off a couple quick tattoos have some coffee and that would be one hell of a day.
So that is something that I'm working on. On the side.
You may have remembered in past videos I've talked about having a thing that's not your thing is very important.
I love photography, I eat breathe, sleep photography, it's even more powerful. Now with the addition of film I just I am all encompassed in this world.
So it's nice to have something fully opposite that I can kind of practice and mess around with and learn that stimulates my creativity.
That is nowhere near taking photos. So it's been really fun and thanks Andrew for putting up with my shaky hands and letting me tattoo garbage on your legs.
Alright, this video is brought to you by artless
our friends over at art list the music in the pirate video we just did with the pirate ship art list, the music in this video artless
recently I've been seeing a lot of comments of people saying like, hey, we really liked the vibe and the feeling and the pace of the videos that you've been making lately.
And one of the changes that Kirk and I decided to make when making videos is taking the music from like kind of an upbeat funk or high energy and slowing it way down to methodical instrumental stuff
that makes you feel nostalgia,
those things are easy to find on artless. So if you do find something you like but it might just not be the right length or there's one little aspect of it, you can find songs that are exactly similar
to what you just had,
which saves you time scouring all of the assets and something that makes creating easy and fun.
There are different subscription plans offered both monthly and annually.
There are pro subscriptions that cover absolutely everything no matter where you're posting your content,
if you want to get two months free on some of those, click the link in the description below, head over to our list and sign up today.
And thank you artless for sponsoring this video and supporting my channel and supporting me and the content that I make on a monthly basis.
And thank you for checking out our list. It's very appreciated.
Next month, I've got a new product launching that has been ready for months
it's out it's probably been years at this point that we've been working on it for at least a year and a half.
But it's it's again looking at it right it's it's gonna be great promo has been filmed photos have been taken, you will be seeing that very, very soon.
So stay tuned for new products, goodness, which is always exciting. Being able to make products is super exciting
physical goods that you can ship and see people using when just that Formula One being able to see all the different filters used by all the media guys from the teams like you're you're running to the
podium and you see Red Bulls already there. And they are they've got a guy filming and they're using a Peter McKinnon filter.
That's, that's insane. That's you randomly bumped into someone leaving Iceland and they happened to be wearing a Peter McKinnon backpack I can't even begin to describe to you how proud and how excited
that makes me so thank you for your support.
And I think you will love what we have coming next month.
It's it's it's been a lot of work and we're all very, very excited for it.
Not long now. Not long. There's three three comments I've been seeing on Office Tour and everyday updated carry, but I feel like that maybe that's that's a pirate channel thing,
and a Chevy update. So there's there's those three things that I've been seeing the Chevy, the 1963 Chevy C 10 is finally done.
And I say finally because Howard put in an ungodly amount of work and love and blood and passion and tears into this truck
to make it the smoothest, nicest ride I have ever experienced driving a vehicle.
So the high score still needs to be beat that stats will probably be part of the office to her if I do it.
Let me know. Let me hear your thoughts
today. Today is the first day of summer. It's also my cousin's birthday, Willie, I love you. Happy birthday.
I forgot his birthday once and he's never let me forget it. He almost forgot mine once until my wife called him at 1150. He texted him and said Don't forget it's pizza birthday.
He squeezed it in one minute before it was over.
And I'm I'm down one nothing to the point where I've actually tattooed his birthday on my wrist. So I would never forget again.
I just I I would love. I would love for him to forget mine.
I don't know why he told you that he's had a huge involvement in this channel behind the scenes with with ideation support and inspiration. So I just felt like it was important to give credit where
credit was due a ghostwriter, if you will
everybody leave comments, happy birthday, Willie.
And then leave a little paramedic sign or something because he saves lives. That's what he does for a living.
Insane. I'm hanging more neons tomorrow because this isn't enough.
I keep looking at this. And I think more than it's getting out of hand.
Just a quick update saying hi, letting you know that I'm still here, I'm still very much working in the background behind the scenes.
But like I said at the beginning of the year, in the video titled you might be seeing less of me that was that was the truth.
I've been trying to figure out a way to communicate my art in a different manner that isn't necessarily three times a week,
the same vlogs you've seen for the last five, six years now on YouTube, I wanted to just have a different approach to video making and that was in fact slowing down
so I don't know that we'll continue that slow for the rest of the year now that we're kind of almost at a halfway point.
But I feel like a video like this was important for me to just let you know that I'm still here.
I still love you. I still care about you. I still care about this channel.
I love it more than I ever have that love for creating only grows bigger plus, you should come see my coffee shop and pirate shop there's a there's a retail space like it's we made a pirate store.
It's cool. That's good coffee.
That's it for me guys. Thanks so much for watching hit the like button if you haven't used to how did I use the end the videos
hit the like button if you liked this video, subscribe if you haven't already and and I will see you in the next video.
And then I'll just undo this little this little thing here and I'll just close up the lens nice and quick right