(ominous music)
[Music]
(dramatic music)
(radio chatter)
(birds chirping)
I've been taking photos for around 17 years now.
And I've been lucky enough to travel the world
with my camera.
Now for the most part, those 17 years,
I've spent using the same cameras and the same lenses.
Trying different focal lengths, different apertures, sure.
But I've mostly stuck with what I know.
It wasn't until recently I picked up a new camera
for the first time.
You know what, I think I'm gonna buy a new camera today.
I went in Rome.
I keep saying that, we're not in Rome.
I feel like we're close proximity.
It inspired me in ways
I didn't think were possible.
I shoot on different
cameras all the time when it comes to
cinematography, documentaries,
projects, video,
but with regards to photography
specifically,
I very rarely
venture outside my walls.
That's where this comes in.
I like it.
- This is pretty cool.
It's really cool.
- This is the Leica Q2 reporter edition.
There's no branding on it, which is sick.
It doesn't have the little red Leica button anywhere.
That's why I like it.
It's almost tactical.
If you're wondering if I wore a green hoodie today
because this camera's green, the answer is yes.
A Leica's have a look to them.
They have a look, they have a feel,
They have a vibe, even though it's a terrible word.
I just hate to say it, but it's true.
And what is great about this and challenging
is that it's got a fixed 28 millimeter 1.7 lens.
You can't switch it for another prime
and there is no switching of the lenses with this camera.
And I love that challenge.
And I feel like it's making me shoot differently
and try to adapt to make this camera work for me
and it's changing my work in the process.
And I find that really, really interesting.
I have a lot of friends that shoot with the Leica Q2.
I can tell the difference when they post Leica photos.
I DM'd a whole bunch of them and was like,
what is the deal with Leica?
Why do you like it so much?
And a lot of them had the same answer.
It just looks different.
It's got a vibe to it.
It's the worst word in 2022, vibe.
(grunts)
But it does.
There's a look to this camera
that I can't quite put my finger on.
Matti and I were reviewing a ton of the shots
that I got in Tofino this last week.
And we were both standing there
looking at the laptop screen thinking,
what is different about?
Is it just like the blacks are blacker
and they're deep and true and just they look so crisp.
It's almost a filmic look to it,
but there's definitely a stylistic something
this camera has that I just feel like
makes it very distinctive.
You just know.
And this video is brought to you by Motion Array.
Motion Array is an unlimited download marketplace
for all your video making needs.
They have over 700,000 premium quality templates,
stock videos, music, and files to help you make videos
faster, better, and easier than ever before.
The best part is probably the fact that they have plugins
for Premiere, so you don't have to technically open
the website and sift through things.
You can just use the plugin.
That makes it super easy to add transitions
and things that other people make through the plugin.
That just speeds up the workflow and ultimately
makes the video look better, more polished.
And you will receive a $50 discount
if you purchase the annual plan.
It's $29.99 a month for unlimited downloads,
unlimited use and all plugins included.
You can get as many assets as you want for one monthly fee.
Or $2.49 for the year for everything that you can do
with a monthly subscription but cheaper.
And if you subscribe through the link
in the description below,
you will save an additional $50 off of that plan
if you are signing up for a year.
So that goes to $1.99 instead of $2.49.
Now you can try it for free if you wanna test it out.
You won't get access to all of the assets,
but you will get access to enough
to see if it's something that you like.
So thanks again to Motion Array for sponsoring this video.
And with that, jump in real quick, this isn't a review,
I'm not deep diving into the Q2,
but more of my experience of how it's made me
kind of change my style as a photographer.
You'll see the shift in my photos on Instagram.
It's like I'm trying to shoot with a more mature mindset,
making it feel a little more fine art.
Maybe that's a phase, I don't know.
Maybe it's the fact that this is a fixed 28 millimeter lens
I can only shoot wide always,
which has produced its own set of challenges.
I wish it had a little more compression
because I love separating the background a bit more,
but that's because it's a 28.
If this Q2 had a 50 millimeter option,
even a 35, I feel like I would prefer that way more.
But the fact that this is like 47 or 48 megapixels,
I forget, it's so sharp.
Like look at Matty's beard right here.
You can crop in so far with this camera,
and that's something that I just never really did.
I know you can do it.
You can do that with any camera.
If you have a camera you can crop, done, sick.
But the attention to detail with not only
the photographic quality but the build quality of this.
It feels like it's milled from a solid piece of titanium.
It's not titanium but right down to the little D.
Like look, this battery catch door,
it pops but it doesn't come all the way out.
You gotta push it again, then it slides.
Mm, I love that.
It looks so good, so sleek.
There's nothing on here that doesn't need to be on here.
There are four buttons on the back of this entire camera.
Three down the side, one wheel, that's it.
Albeit there's a lot of like weird long press
and hold press and stuff to custom function.
If you get the hang of it, it's probably fine.
Again, I've been using this for like a month
and it's one of those things that you can just
carry around with you and use it on your family outings
or just have it as your secondary kind of personal camera.
I haven't done that for so long, so long.
I've been shooting with the same gear for 15 years
and I love it but it's been nice to just
step outside my comfort zone and try something entirely new.
I'm standing out there on the beach in Tofino
taking snapshots of people,
literally trying to figure out how to use a camera again.
And there's something nice about that challenge
that I haven't felt in such a long time.
It's the same feeling that back when I used to do
a ton of magic, you do magic for so long, you're a magician.
Tricks don't really fool you anymore.
When someone's performing for you,
you can kinda just see everything
that's happening behind the scenes.
Even if you don't see it,
you know the moves that were being done.
So once in a while when you do get fooled
and you feel like a kid again, experiencing magic,
like when you first got into it, that's refreshing.
And I feel like this has done kind of the same thing for me
but for photography.
So this video I wanted to make
to kind of share my inspiration with trying something new.
Maybe it's a technique, maybe it's a lens,
maybe it's an entire new system,
maybe it's just going somewhere different.
I don't know, but stepping outside the comfort zone
and away from what I'm just so good at and comfortable with
made me re-appreciate and refocus my goals in photography
to start trying new stuff, and I'm grateful for that.
So are you switching brands?
Ah, Peter, he's gone, he's like a,
nah, it's just a camera, it's a tool,
and it's making me see things differently.
That's it, I'm excited.
Life is good.
Brought to you by Motion Array.
Motion Array.
Motion Ray.
(imitating air whooshing)
Brought to you by Motion.
A ray.
I don't know why I did any of that.
Get rekt, Kirk.
(laughs)
Just added 40 minutes to his day.