Unknown: Hey I haven't seen you for a while.
Hi. what's up what's up I haven't done one of those for a bit
Peter: I wanted to take this time to give a little bit of a life update health update.
You know it's just one of those little heart to hearts.
It's probably long overdue Formula one in Abu Dhabi was insane.
Got a new camera, Iceland video is coming and it's awesome office is coming along very, very nicely stoked for that
travel isn't done this year still got a couple more under the belt to get through before Christmas time
and some things that have been happening behind the scenes pay for old time stakes to another level
Okay, I just got back from Dubai and Abu Dhabi.
I flew with my wife and Maddie and his wife to the UAE for the Formula One race race day was actually on our wedding anniversary.
So that was super cool. My wife's first race had an absolute blast to all my friends that made it happen that got us out there that hooked up garage tours and made the experience special.
You know who you are. Thank you very much. What a blast.
And interestingly enough, I didn't use my camera very much at all.
Actually, on race day, I didn't even bring my q2,
I usually bring that everywhere. It's strapped behind my back.
But I just went with a phone on race day and it felt great.
It felt great to just walk in there like a human being went and I enjoyed and I loved every minute of that.
So some quick updates, I bought a new camera, expect a new video about a new camera that you haven't seen before on this channel.
I'm very, very excited. It's the same color as my other camera.
That's all I'm gonna say for now.
Update number two, this Iceland video slaps
I had a 25 minute super cut going which I think I'll still post it's more of like a big vlog kind of super cut have fun moments from this Iceland adventure Matty and I went on,
Unknown: I condensed it all the way down to two minutes. And we started something new,
Peter: which just basically gave us two pieces of content now that are both incredible.
But I'm very, very excited about the short form one so that'll be posting soon.
Keep an eye out for that. But good things take time.
Now one of the reasons this Isilon video has taken us so long to do is because we decided to handmake every single visual aspect within this little piece.
So frame by frame motion graphics take a long time to do well.
In hindsight, I should have just used motion array,
obviously time being a massive, massive factor in this
instead of hunting for assets, then trying to figure out how to use them how to learn the software
gets your videos done faster and makes things easier, but it keeps your inspiration levels high.
Because the longer you spend on a project, typically that project starts to annoy you, you start to get tired of it, you start to just want it to be done.
You start to scrutinize things you nitpick and Done is better than perfect. I've said that for years on this channel.
And I think motion array kind of fits in well with that because it gets the project done instead of trying to make it perfect.
So here motion array makes sense for the business if it makes sense for your business.
And it's not just motion graphic templates, but it's assets of all kinds.
For instance, if I wanted some text to come on the screen, right, as I said, here are some snapshots from Iceland
that took way less time than you would expect.
Now had I actually tried to learn the software and do that that would be hours and hours and hours of my day for a part of the video that took what less than 10 seconds.
It's the low hanging fruit here. They've got pricing monthly, they've got pricing for the year.
It's one of those things where when you compound the value that you get from this it far outweighs what it costs especially when you're thinking about the long term
so thank you to motion array for sponsoring this video.
Check out the link below but I digress.
Iceland is coming soon. Keep an eye out for that video. Super super excited other things in the news I am opening a Pete's pirate life shop downtown Toronto at the clocks and colors flagship store
that is opening in December
so there might be like a little bit of a meet up there might be a little bit of a grand opening party
if there is I'm waiting on a confirmation today.
So once I get that confirmation I'll make some posts because it'd be cool.
If you're in the area you want to come down hang out check out the new flagship check out the pirate stuff check out everything clocks and colors have been working so hard on
I'm very very excited to have a physical shop downtown Toronto so very excited for that.
There will also be a small pop up shop downstairs.
Once my office is done
that could be the next point the office downstairs chapter five
it's coming along electrical most of the framing is done slick. I do lights and paint and drywall The floors are done concrete has been grinded
but I'm super excited to be back on Main Street with a place that we can do whatever we want. went with and make entirely our own very very pumped
travel isn't done this year. It's literally been a record breaking year for travel
but a lot of it I haven't filmed because some of these projects have been kind of top secret that I wasn't allowed to post or showcase yet
so instead of just saying, Hey, I'm off to wherever tomorrow, but I can't talk about it. I just literally didn't talk about it.
For example. Don't think you're gonna think it's happening?
Yes, a very exciting very quick trip that video will also be coming soon ready to go. Now one of the big things is I've been sick for what feels like months now.
I when I got home from Iceland, I got the worst flu I've ever had in my life. I thought it was COVID tested like three or four times they were all negative
when I had COVID It was literally easier than whatever this was knocked me out entirely had to cancel my Austin trip to Formula One that's how bad it was.
There was absolutely no way I could even leave the bedroom recovered from that kids got sick. I got sick again.
And then literally in the middle of the night, my eardrum burst something I did not expect.
I had no idea was coming and I can confirm it is the worst pain I've almost ever experienced.
Highly not recommended if it ever happens.
I feel very sorry for you. I have sympathy because it sucks.
Now the big concern was flying to the UAE for 12 to 15 hours with a busted eardrum but the doctor said because there's a hole in it, the pressure won't build because it's already broken.
And they were right. It didn't hurt at all. So it was pretty stressful leading up to I was very anxious just I had an ear infection once on an aeroplane and it was total garbage.
So we got to the UAE just busted eardrum fine. But then I started feeling under the weather once I landed in the UAE it's been a journey.
And I feel like I'm still not 100% Now, but I'm coming out the other side of it with all of this.
I tried to just kind of take it easy and relax and realize that health is more important. And mental health is more important than trying to force out videos.
When I'm just feeling completely down and defeated. As far as health goes
happy to say I'm back. I'm feeling good. I'm feeling better. I'm feeling on the other side of things. I'm fired up. I'm very blessed and very grateful to be able to do this every single day.
Go on these adventures. Meet these cool people make cool projects work with great people.
And thank you. Thank you for watching. Thank you for subscribing and giving me this opportunity. Thank you for your time.
All right, I was trying to keep this like a quick update. But you know, not very good at that.
Oh, the angels and airwaves documentary. Yes. I'm still making it. It's still underway. If you haven't noticed. There are lots of developments happening right now in that industry.
So good stories take time. That's one thing I've learned within making this documentary.
It's not a YouTube video. Things need to unfold life needs to unfold. I need to be patient and be there for those things unfolding to tell the best story that I possibly can.
Okay, that's it. I love you guys. I'm gonna get back to finishing this Iceland video and then I'm going to blow your minds.